ILGWU Myrtle Banks Photographs 5780/212 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Myrtle Banks Photographs
1956-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Banks, Myrtle
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/212 P
1.61 cubic feet
1.6 linear ft.
Photographs.
This collection includes photographs of Myrtle Banks' retirement party in 1984, events at the City of Hope medical center, local union meetings, and ILGWU conventions.
7010058
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 28, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Myrtle Banks was born in North Little Rock, Arkansas in 1919, and in 1946, began work in California's garment industry, and became a member of in the Dressmakers' Union Local 101 in San Francisco. In 1961, after fifteen years working as a garment worker and, for a time, serving as shop steward at Koret of California in San Francisco, Myrtle Banks became a business agent with the ILGWU. In 1984, Banks retired from her position as business representative in the Pacific Northwest District Council. Throughout her career, she served as Chair of the Alameda County Chapter of the A. Philip Randolph Institute, Vice President of the Alameda County Civil Service Commission, and Trustee of the San Francisco Joint Board.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes photographs of Myrtle Banks' retirement party in 1984, events at the City of Hope medical center, local union meetings, and ILGWU conventions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/212 MB: ILGWU Myrtle Banks Memorabilia
Clothing workers -- Labor unions; Textile workers -- Labor unions; Banks, Myrtle
7010058
- Contents of a Photo Album, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Photographs Included
- "City of Hope" Photo Album, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photo Album Contents (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Retirement Pictures [Office] & Union Party, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Photographs; 13 of Retirement
- Miami Beach, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Loose" Photographs, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Union. New Orleans (Box 1, Folder 7)
- A.P.R.I. Washington D.C., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Union Meeting. Fashion Show, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  March 1; Photographs Included
- Union Meeting. Fashion Show, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Photographs Included. May
- Union Convention. Herbert F. Humphrey, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  May; Photographs Included
- "Loose" Photographs, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mary Clemente, Mattie May, Larry & Me (Box 1, Folder 13)
- May 1956 Convention & Union, 1956-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Union August 29; Photographs Included
- Korset X-Mas Party, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  December 24; Photographs Included
- Union Hall (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Union. M.M. Gauks, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Myrtle & Union, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Local 101. Halloween Party (Box 1, Folder 19)
- UFWOC & Grape Strike, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- City of Hope Fundraiser & Union Float (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Union Picnic (Box 1, Folder 22)
- L.B.J. Union (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Union Convention (Box 1, Folder 24)
- County Fair, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Union Picnic (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Guiton Buses
- Konocte Conference Pictures, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  January 21; Chinese Included
- Sam Clemente. Union Photographs (Box 1, Folder 28)
  June 16
- Miscellaneous Union Photographs, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Photography Album Contents (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Group Photograph (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Rolled photographs [5], 1956-1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  32nd Convention, Miami Beach 1965, ILGWU; Atlantic City, N.J., May, 10-18, 1956, ILGWU (brittle with a couple tears); 33rd Convention, International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Atlantic City, N.J. May 23rd to 30th, 1968; 34th Convention, Internation
- Photo Album 1 [Folder 1 of 2], 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  June
- Photo Album 1 [Folder 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  May
- Photo Album, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- A. Phillip Randolph. 31st ILG Convention. Almeda County Civil Service Commission, 1962-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Honoring W. March. Atlantic City (6/1962)
- Photo Album 2 [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Pin Included; Myrtle Banks and Others
- Photo Album 2 [Folder 2 of 2], 1956/1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Myrtle Banks and others
- 5 Panoramic Photos - see list in 'notes', 1956-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  ILGWU - Atlantic City, NJ - May, 10-18, 1956; 34th Convention, ILGWU, AFL-CIO, Miami Beach, Florida - May 6-15, 1971; 32nd Convention, ILGWU - Miami Beach 1965; Twenty-Ninth Convention - ILGWU, AFL-CIO - Atlantic City, NJ - May 10-18, 1956; 33rd Conve
- 5 panoramic photos (Box 3)